life like said welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer will we open up with the 10
commandments that God commanded the
world to keep brother Tel and God spake
all these words saying I am the Lord thy
God which have brought thee out of the
land of Egypt out of the house of
bondage thou shall have no other gods
before me thou not make to thee any
Graven image or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above or that in the
earth beneath or that is in the water
under the Earth thou shall not bow down
thyself to them nor serve them for the
Lord that God I'm a jealous God visiting
the iniquities of the fathers upon the
children unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me and
showing Mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my Commandments
thou shall not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain for the Lord will not
hold him Guiltless that take of his name
in vain remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy six days shall thou labor and do
all thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God in it thou
shall not do any work thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter thy man servant nor thy
maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy Gates when
six days the Lord made Heaven and Earth
the sea and all that in them is and
rested the seven day wherefore the Lord
blessed the Sabbath day and hollowed it
honor thy father and thy mother
that thy days may be long upon the land
which the Lord thy God giveth thee thou
shall not kill thou shall not commit
adultery thou shall not steal thou sh
not bear false witness against thy
neighbor thou sh not cover thy
neighbor's house thou shall not cover
thy neighbor's wife nor his man servant
nor his maid servant nor his Ox nor his
ass nor anything that is thy neighbors
we read Exodus 21-17 and may the Lord
have a blessing to the reading of his
words in Jesus name we pray amen
amen so he on question and answer you
can ask us a question and we'll answer
it according to the King James Bible and
if we cannot find the answer we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time keep in mind it
all B questions will not be answered and
all long scripture questions will not be
answered for time sake so please be as
direct as possible with your questions
out of the King James Bible so we can be
as direct as possible
with our answers out of the King James
Bible no other Bibles will be
acknowledged on this program also keep
in mind that this is a live stream and
you may begin to send in your questions
at this time even questions that pertain
to everlasting life we're just asking
that you keep your questions to a two
scripture maximum and also on atonement
October the 13th at 3M we will be having
a Q&A that's on Sunday after the lesson
all right sister Deborah let me
introduce the family that's on the panel
this evening brother Jerome Grace in
peace Brother
Julius good evening
everybody brother Dre good evening
brother tanzel good evening sister
Deborah good
evening uh sister Casey is with us and
we also have the guest caller with us
and I'm brother Cornell but sister
Deborah what is our first question of
the yes uh there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into the into tonight's
Q&A uh Doc Martin says I heard you say
we are in the first Heavens so when God
returns will this Earth be considered a
heaven all right will this Earth be
considered a heaven brother Jerome what
you
got uh yes um what we know is three
heavens and you can uh read that in
second Corinthians chap 12 verse
1-2 But to answer your question um when
God the son returned to this Earth this
Earth will still be re referred to as a
heaven okay so let's go to Matthew
chapter 24 let's read about the second
coming of the
Lord Matthew 24 and we're going to read
verse 29-31 and then we're going to go
to uh Deuteronomy 30 after that
K when you get it go ahead and
read immediately after the tribulation
of those days shall the Sun be darkened
and the moon should not give her light
and the Stars shall fall from Heaven and
the powers of the heaven shall be
shaken and then shall appear the sign of
the son of man in heaven and then shall
all the tribes of the earth mourn and
they shall see the son of man coming in
the Clouds Of Heaven with power and
great Glory he shall send his angels
with a great sound of a trumpet and they
shall gather together his elect from the
Four Winds and one end of Heaven to the
other yeah and Heaven in this case in
that 31st verse is talking about the
first Heaven this Earth okay now let's
go to Deuteronomy chapter 30 and read
verses
1-5 you get it go ahead and read and it
shall come to pass when all these things
are come upon thee the blessings and the
curse which I have set before thee and
thou shall call them to mind among all
the nations whether the Lord thy God ha
driven thee and shall turn unto the Lord
thy God and shall obey his voice
according to all that I command thee
this day thou and thy children with all
thy heart and with all thy soul that
then the Lord thy God will turn thy
captivity and have compassion upon thee
and will return and gather thee from all
the nations whether the Lord thy God
have scattered thee and if any of thine
be driven out into the outmost parts of
Heaven from then will the Lord thy God
gather thee and from then will he fetch
thee and the Lord thy God will bring
thee into the land which thy father
possess and thou shalt possess it and he
will do thee good and multiply thee
above thy fathers yeah so all the
children of Israel that's going to be
gathered they're going to be on this
Earth but he referred to it as the
uttermost parts of heaven so that's the
first Heaven okay now the the father
even when he come this earth going to
still be referred to as a heaven okay so
let's go to Psalms 148 and we just going
to read three verses and that'll be it
Psalms
148 and read verse 4
through6 you get it go
ahead Praise Him ye heavens of heavens
and ye Waters that be above the heavens
let them praise the name of the Lord for
he commanded and they were created he
have also established them forever and
ever he have made a decree which shall
not pass yeah and so the reason why you
see uh Heavens in plural because we know
that it's three and he said in that
sixth verse uh they they were establish
forever and ever that's all I got on
me all right thank you for that brother
as we move on to our next
question uh yes Shirley White uh asks
why would Jesus always heal someone he
would tell them not to go and tell like
in Matthew 12 verse
16 all right why when Jesus always heal
somebody he would say for them not to go
and let it be known and it begins in
that
Matthew let's go to that Matthew 12
verse6 the guest caller take it from
there brother tangel
and charge them that they should not
make him
known
okay he made that statement in this
particular case and some other but not
always but I'm going to tell you why he
said it in this case let's back up to
Matthew the N 12 12th chapter still but
read verse 9 and Skip down and we're
going to read from verse 13 to
21 verse 9 first Matthews 12
and9 and when he was departed then he
went into their
synagogues verse 13
right yeah
then read a little
more and
behold and read a little bit
more you and n and read uh uh read all
the nine you didn't read all the 12 and
nine
Matthew the 12th chapter verse 9
okay n and 10 okay now read verse
10 okay and behold there was a man which
had his hand withered and they asked him
saying is it lawful to heal on the
Sabbath days that they might accuse
him and let's see what he did now skip
down to 13
then say he to the man stretch forth thy
hand and he stretched it forth and it
was restored whole like as the
other uhuh the Pharisees went out and
held a counsel against him how they
might destroy
himal Sabbath day they they they come
together andig trying to figure out how
they going to kill him go ahead but when
Jesus knew it he would JW himself from V
and the great multitude followed him and
he healed the all and charg and charged
them that they should not make make
known him make him
known now this is the first reason
because the Pharisees was trying to kill
him so he just withdrew himself and and
when he and and when he he heal other
people he said don't don't tell them
where I am you understand what I'm
saying but then the first reason but the
second reason he had to fulfill prophecy
keep
reading that it might be fulfilled which
was spoken by Isaiah the prophet saying
behold my servant whom I have chosen my
beloved in whom my soul is well pleased
and I will put my spirit upon him and he
shall show judgment to the
Gentiles he shall not strive nor cry
neither shall any man hear his voice in
the streets the bruised Reed shall he
not break and smoking flax shall he not
quench till he send forth judgment unto
Victory and in his name shall the
Gentiles
trust now now that is the second reason
because the fulfilled prophecy what
prophecy go to Isaiah the chapter
42 and we going to read 1 through
4 behold
behold my servants whom I uphold my
elect in whom I Soul Delight I have put
my spirit upon him and he shall bring
forth judgment to the Gentiles he shall
not cry or lift up nor cause his voice
to be heard in the streets and the
bruised reath shall he not break and the
smoking flax shall he not quench he
shall bring forth judgment unto truth he
shall not fail nor be discouraged till
he have set judgment in the earth and
the
shall wait
for so there was two reasons he didn't
want him to say nothing because he was
hiding out from the frany that was
trying to kill it and then the other
reason is he had to fulfill
prophecy prophecy that we just read
don't have to say all right thank you
for that sister Deborah as we move on to
our next question next question Sanders
hering says need some clarification
Hebrews 9 verse 7 concerning the second
Veil is this meaning the holy Place
mercy seat behind the first Veil and he
also asks about Micah 4 verse 8 who is
the Tower of the flock could this be
Israel all right first question is that
clarification on that Hebrews 9 verse 7
so when you get there tanzel go ahead
and read guest caller we'll take it from
there go ahead read but into the second
went the high priest alone once every
year not without blood which he' offer
for himself and for the errors of the
people now right there he said a second
Veil but there ain't but one
Veil for the veil is called a holy place
and after the veil is called the holiest
of all of the most over the place now
let's go into into uh Leviticus the 4th
chapter and we going to read from one to
six and Skip down and read verse
20 go ahead when you get
there and the Lord spake unto Moses
saying Speak unto the children of Israel
saying if a soul shall sin through
ignorance against any other Commandments
of the Lord concerning things which
ought not to be done and shall do
against any of them if the priest that
is Anointed do sin according to the sin
of the people then let him bring for his
sin which he have Sinn a young Bullock
without blemish unto the Lord for a sin
offering and he shall bring the Bullock
unto the door of the Tabernacle of the
congregation before the Lord and shall
lay his hand upon the Bullock's head and
kill the bulock before the Lord and the
priest that is Anointed shall take of
the Bullock's blood and bring it to the
Tabernacle of the congregation and the
preach of Di in the blood and sprinkle
of the blood seven times before the Lord
before the veil of the
sanctuary now now that happens every day
he was doing that and and what happened
when he sprinkled the veil skip blood
before the veil skip down to verse 20
and read it he shall do with the bulock
as he did with the Bullock for a sin
offering so shall he do with this and
the priest shall make an atonement for
them and it shall be forgiv
them and he shall be forgiven now that
happens every day in front of the veil
but now once a year on the day of
atonement the priest went within the
veil cuz it ain't but one let's get that
in Leviticus the 16th
chapter 1 2 3 and then we're going to
skip
now and the Lord spake unto Moses after
the death of the two sons of Aaron when
they offered before the Lord and died
and the Lord said unto Moses speak unto
Aaron thy brother that he come not at
all times unto the holy place within the
veil before the mercy seat which is upon
the ark that he die not for I will
appear in the clouds upon The Mercy
Seat
that's he told Moses you tell a not to
come in here at all time you know like
before in in front of the veil right
that he die not but he told to come one
uh come one time what verse was that
that was in
two go ahead read
three thus shall Lon come into the holy
place with a young bullly for a sin
offering and a real for a burnt
offering now he had to come in with two
animals one for him and one for and a
RAM for a burnt offen and that's within
the veil only on the uh uh uh uh day of
Pentecost now skip
down did you finish on atonement I'm
sorry a day of atonement did you finish
that yeah I was in the three y to verse
29 go
ahead and this shall be a statute
forever un that in the seven month on
the 10th day of the month ye shall
afflict your souls and do no work at all
whether it be one of your own country or
Strang that sourth among
you for on that day shall the priest
make an atonement for you to cleanse you
that you may be clean from all your sins
before the Lord and it shall be a
Sabbath of rest unto you you and you
shall afflict your souls by Statue
forever and the
priest what verse is that that was the
end of
31 y down to verse
34 and this shall be an everlasting
statue unto you to make an atonement for
the children of Israel for all their
sins once a year he did as the Lord
commanded
Moses now every day they went before the
Veil and made sin offering for the
people but only once a year on the day
of atonement they went within the
veil and made and made an atonement for
the whole
nation so not but one veil in the front
of the veil is called the holy place and
behind the veil is the most holy place
that's where the mercy seat and
everything is back there the Ark of the
Covenant right you know and and uh uh
and the Sher of angels on each side of
the the mercy sea
but one Veil but you have two places in
front is the holy place behind is the
most holy
place okay for the second one is Micah 4
and8 read
it and thou oh Tower of the flock the
stronghold of the daughter of Zion unto
thee shall it come even the first
Dominion the kingdom shall come to the
daughter of
Jerusalem okay so they want to know the
to of the flock is let's go into uh uh
uh uh Isaiah chapter 22 we're going to
read three and and Skip down to verse 50
and
51 Isaiah 22 pick up at verse
three just read verse three then we
going to skip to 50 and
51 read all th rulers are fled together
they are bound by The Arches all that
are found now in thee are bound together
with have fled from
Far uhhuh skip down to
50 uh let we go to
25 oh you you're in second Samuel
right no no
Isaiah
22 I'm sorry 2 Samuel
22 okay
verse
three the god of my rock in him will I
trust he is my shield and the Horn of my
salvation my high tower and my refuge My
Savior thou sawest me from V savest me
from
violence let you look that the Lord is
his high tower skip down now what verse
are that was the end of
three now skip down to 50 and read 50
and 51
therefore I will give thanks unto thee
Oh Lord among the heathens and I will
sing praises unto thy name he is the
Tower of salvation for his King and show
Mercy to his anointed unto David and to
his sea forever
more so the Lord is the
tower otherwise and and and the other
part of it he's talking about uh uh
um about his uh uh uh
what did we call it let didn't get the
rest of it let's see he was saying who
is the Tower of the flock could it could
this be
Israel no that's that's Jesus and the
other one he said that and he uh let's
let's go it'll tell us who it is and the
stronghold he said who is this
stronghold let's go into uh
um Isaiah the nth chapter
and we're going to read from
12 no not not Isaiah Zechariah the 9th
chapter Zechariah Chapter 9 and we're
going to read from 9 to
12 zear
n Go ahe when you get
there so Zechariah 9 start at verse 9
yeah Rejoice greatly oh Daughter of Zion
shout oh daughter of Jerusalem Behold
thy King cometh unto thee he is just and
having salvation lowly and riding upon
an ass and upon a coat the fold of an
ass and I will cut off and I will cut
off The Chariot from Ephraim and the
horse from Jerusalem and the battle boat
shall be cut off and he shall speak
peace unto the heathens and his Dominion
shall be from sea even to Sea and from
the river even to the ends of the Earth
as for thee also by the blood of thy
Covenant I have sent forth thy prisoners
out of the pit wherein is no water so
turn you to the stronghold ye prisoners
of Hope even today do I declare that I
will render double unto
thee so now Jesus is the is is the
stronghold for all that people that have
hope people of the uh prisoners of hope
they will hope in his
salvation okay right
here I have to
say the tower here the tower and he he
the strong
mod okay all right thank you for that
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next moving on Ben F ask
is there anything related to smoking
marijuana that go against anything in
the
Bible so Julius what about smoking
marijuana is there anything in that
Bible the King James
Bible the Bible says nothing for or
against smoking
marijuana that's that's my answer all
right yep and uh make sure you do your
homework some job still will test you
and take your job so make sure you on
top for your
homework all right hope that answered
your question our next question next
question Zion says could you explain
Ephesians 6
verse2 Ephesians 6 and 12 what you say
Dre oh let's go to Ephesians 6 and we
gonna read verses 11 and
12 go ahead brother when you get
it put on the whole arm of God that you
may be able to stand against the Ws of
the devil for be wrestle not against
flesh and blood but against
principalities against Powers against
the ruler of the doctrines of this world
against spiritual wickedness in high
places yeah so this this Warfare that
you have is
spiritual and and it starts with you
right starts with your thinking and how
you deal with things but we're not w
wrestling against flesh and blood you
know we we dealing with
principalities against Powers the rulers
of the darkness of this world let's go
to uh Second Corinthians
10 2 Corinthians
10 and read verses three and four when
you get there go ahead
brother second Corinthians
Al though we walk in the flesh we do not
war after the
flesh for the weapons of our Warfare are
not carnal But Mighty through God
through the pulling down of strongholds
and the weapons of our Warfare is
spiritual and that is the word of God
that's right that word has to be in you
because the war is on and it's at every
hand and so the first war is with us in
our thinking and we have to put on the
whole armor of God read verse
five casting down imaginations and every
High thing that exalt itself against the
knowledge of God and bringing into
captivity every thought to The Obedience
of Christ that is it so that's what that
Ephesians uh 6 and 12 is dealing with
it's that war
so I hope that that helps and that that
your armor is walking in the word of
God that's it all right thank you for
that brother hope that answered that
question as we move on to our next
moving on barer still asks how do you
pray in the spirit I used to think that
was when you were praying and you just
started unly in tongues
all right brother Julius what you got
think that people are getting two things
confused they're talking about praying
in this there's a difference between
praying in the spirit and praying with
the spirit let's go to 1 Corinthians the
14th chapter well first let's go to
Ephesians chapter 6 and then I got one
place after
this Ephesians chapter 6 brother tenzel
and look what Paul said about praying in
the spirit praying in the spirit is is
praying in the privacy of your own mind
in
silence praying in the privacy of your
own mind in silence Ephesians 6 and8 go
ahead and read it praying always with
all prayer and supplication in the
spirit and watching there unto with all
P perseverance and supplication for All
Saints so when you are praying in the
spirit you are in agreeance with the
word of God for whatever you're praying
for okay you're in agreeance with the
word of God because some people just
pray with no without understanding you
could pray outside the spirit Also let's
go to First Corinthians the 14th
chapter because this is where I think
that people get things mixed up they
think that praying is spirit and you
break out into some kind of tongue let's
look what Paul said about
that 1 Corinthians 14 and pick it up at
verse 13 if you read the whole chapter
it would tell you that tongues which is
another language is for unbelievers but
pick it up at verse 13 and go ahead
wherefore let him that speaketh in an
unknown tongue pray that he may
interpret go ahead or if I pray in an
unknown tongue my spirit prayer but my
understanding is unfruitful he said my
spirit prayer but my understand is
unfruitful this is why you see people
praying in church and they speaking in
tongue but no but there's no interpreted
so things are out of order
continue what is it then I will pray
with the spirit and I will pray with the
understanding also so when you're
praying in the spirit you have to have
the understanding of what you are
praying for and it's got to be written
or it's got to be an agreeance with the
word of God continue and I was seen with
the spirit and I was seen with the
understanding also and I was seen with
the understanding also so you got to
understand this one more verse
else when thou shall bless with the
spirit how shall he that occupy the room
of the unlearned say Amen at TH giving
of thanks seeing he understandeth not
what thou sayest so now but they got it
backwards today there are people are
speaking in tongue and churches and
they're saying amen there's no
interpreter there's not one or two
interpreters and people are saiding amen
so be it because everybody speaking in
tongue but nobody's understanding and
that is confusing in the church so
praying in the spirit is praying when
you praying uh in the spirit you are
praying in the Silence of your own mind
and it should be in agreeance with the
word of God that's all I got I hope that
helps all right thank you for that
brother sister Deborah time check as we
move on yes the time is
8:01 we can talk right here as what is
the difference between wanting something
bad
and lusting after
something well there is a difference and
and a big difference you can want
something bad you know I want salvation
real bad therefore I'm waiting on it and
patience is a good thing to have and
sometime inside of lust people do not
have patience and that flesh can get
them to sin against God turn to James
the first chapter James the first
chapter but sometimes you want something
bad and it's good and and uh then you
have to be
patient sometime lust is hey right now
and I Gotta Have It even though it might
be the wrong thing to do James 1 pick it
up at that verse uh
13 and let's see what it say about
lusting for something but wanting
something real bad when it's good for
you that's a good thing go ahead let no
man say when he is tempted I am tempted
of God
for God cannot be tempted with evil
neither tempt he any man uhhuh every man
is tempted when he is drawn away from
his own lust and entice also so every
man is tempted when he is drawn away of
his own lust and entice because sometime
that flesh say I gotta have it and I got
to have it now but it can be against God
and you lust him for things sometimes
that should not be verse
15 then when lust have conceived it
bringeth forth sin and sin when it is
finished bringeth forth death so when
that lust is won and you have done
something you shouldn't shouldn't do
bring forth sin and that sin can bring
forth death and you do not want to have
that on your report now turn over to
John 8 John the eth
chapter and let's see because
lust is where Satan dwells and where he
hangs out at and you have to be very
careful that let's read us one verse
here Tel let's read that John the 8th
chapter and pick it up at that verse
44 go ahead my
brother ye are of your father the devil
and the lust of your father ye will do
see you are following the lust of Satan
when you are doing things that are not
right go ahead he was a murderer from
the beginning and ab B not in the truth
because there is no truth in and when he
speak of for Li he speak of his own for
he is a liar and the father of it indeed
he is so that's all I got on that
because there is a difference between
hey wanting something bad that's okay
when it's good for you but lusting I
Gotta Have It gotta have it now I know
it ain't right you are crossing the line
even in your own mindset if you don't
correct that that's all I
get all right we hope that that answered
your question as we keep
moving keep moving
Israelite by Blood Brandon says IO
travel to further locations to baptize
I'm located in Iowa is there any way you
guys can travel to baptize me
please brother that is a good thing that
you we understand that you want to be
baptized that's a good thing and if we
can accommodate we certainly will but
why don't you call office and let's have
a
conversation all right this is not
something we'll address right here just
call the office let's have a
conversation and take it from
there all right we're gonna move on to
our next question next question be alert
as in 2 Chronicles 24 no verses given
was joash 7 when began to
rain all right second Chronicles
24 and I believe that's going to be that
verse one and two but the guest caller
would take it from there um brother
tanzel because it's asking about his age
and I think it will say his age right
there pick it up at that 2 Chronicles 24
And1 and the guest caller take it from
there was he
seven the joaz was 7 years old when he
began to Reign and he reigned 40 years
in Jerusalem his mother also the
mother's name also was zah of be
Sheba yes
was yes he was seven years when he
started and the reason it was that is
because his grandmother was a evil woman
let's go in uh let's go into uh Second
Kings the 10th
chapter 11 chapter brother second king
second king the 11th chapter
then we going to
skip you go ahead when you get there and
the seventh year Jehovah sent and Fest
the rulers over hundreds and with the
captains and guards and the guards and
brought them to him into the house of
the Lord and made a covenant with them
wait a minute wait a
minute you what I say Second Kings right
Second Kings
11 vers 4
right
uhuh let me make sure make sure this is
the right
place let's
see verse one I want you to start it 11
and one okay go
ahead and when at the liar the mother of
azias saw that her son was dead she
arose and destroyed all the seed
Royal now analiah the only woman that
ever ruled in Israel at any time and her
son got killed jeu killed her son aazah
and when she saw that her son was dead
he rose up and killed all the Royal seed
all his children he
read but jehosheba the daughter of King
Jam uh sister of a aziah took joaz the
son of aziah and stole uh stole him from
among the king's Sons which were slain
and they hear him even him and his nurse
in the bed Chamber from aah so that he
was not
slain and he was with her hid her in the
house of the Lord six years and a li did
rain over the land and
the while do evil grandmother was was
riging uh uh his nurse took him into the
house of the Lord and hid him for six
years read the next verse the seven
years Jehovah do sent and fetched the
rulers over hundreds and the captains
and the gods and brought them to him
into the house of the Lord and made a
covenant with them and took an oath of
them in the house of the Lord and showed
them the King's
son now so what he did was that jeor was
the priest he was helping hide him for
seven years and so now in the seventh
year he called all the people together
because they was going to anoint this
boy let's skip down to verse 12 and read
it and he brought forth the King's son
and put the crown upon him and gave him
the testimony and they made him King and
anointed him and they clapped their
hands and said God Save the King now he
was nothing but a child 7 years old get
down to verse 20 and read verse 20 and
21 and all the people of the land
rejoiced and the city was in quiet and
they slew a liar with a sword beside the
King's house seven years old was jeho
jehoash when he began to
reain so when evil grandmother heard
about it she going to come to the temple
all the trees and treason you can read
all that on your own but they killed her
and they set him on the throne he was
seven years old and that priest
uh uh raised him was with him until he
got
grown that's all have to say yes he was
seven years old yep that's a good
example too she live by the sword and
she died by the
sword all right hope that answered your
question as we keep on
moving keep on moving Jun nor for asks
in Genesis 8 verse two is it possible
that Windows of Heaven is talking about
the body of water above the fit or is
this just the
clouds Windows of heaven we talking
about the clouds in this instance but
let's go they said Genesis
8 and verse two verse two yes all right
Genesis 8 and let's read uh let's read
one and two 10
okay Genesis eight pick up every yep one
and two brother and God remembered Noah
and every living thing and all the
cattle that was with him in the ark and
God made a wind to pass over the earth
and the waters a
sway and the fountain also the deep and
the windows of Heaven were stocked and
the rain from heaven was restrained all
right so The Fountains of the deep and
it's a separation of the windows of
heaven so the Lord break up the ground
to bring water up and he also rain water
down let's go in Genesis one Genesis
1 we get to that Genesis 1 brother pick
it up at that verse
six Genesis one and pick it up at verse
six because the word firmate here is a
can be used as a can have two meanings
one is expansion and other one can be
the sky depends on how it's being used
but Genesis 1 and verse 6 go ahead
brother and God said let there be a
firmament in the midst of the waters let
it divide the waters from the waters oh
let it be affirmate in the midst of the
waters so the Lord separated the water
on the earth from the water that's right
under the third heaven go ahead and God
made the firmament and divided the
waters which were under the firmament
from the waters which were above the
firmament and it was so yes so we
talking about some sky here now using
that word firmament verse eight and God
called the firmament Heaven and the
evening and the morning were the second
day and God called the fent heaven so we
are talking about the sky in general
itself right there all right skip down
to verse 14 brother and go ahead and God
said let there be lights in the
firmament of the heaven to divide the
day from the night now we see we use
affirming the sky go
ahead and let them be for signs and for
season and for days and years Y and let
them be for lights in the firmament of
the heaven to give light upon the Earth
and it was
so and God made two great lights the
Great light to Rule the Day and the
Lesser light to rule the night and he
made the Stars also yes all right so I
just wanted to show that word firmate
there but let's go into that Genesis 7
Genesis 7 and read verse one and then we
go Skip and read 11 and 12 go ahead and
the Lord said unto Noah Come Thou and
all thy house until the yard for thee
have I seen righteous before me in this
generation
yeah skip down
11 and the 600 year of Noah's life in
the second month the 17 day of the month
the same day were all The Fountains of
the great deep broken up and the windows
of Heaven were open and the windows of
Heaven were open that's where we were
you were asking about the clouds so when
you hear that word Windows of Heaven the
Lord is talking about up in the sky
there and when he opened the windows of
Heaven what happened verse 12 that's the
last verse in that go ahead and the rain
was upon the Earth 40 days and 40 night
yeah so one other place Ecclesiastes 11
and one verse Ecclesiastes 11 and we'll
go read one
verse because they want to know about
the Firmin it and they wanted to know
about the clouds here so let's go
ecclesiast 11 and just read one verse
for me brother and that would be that
verse three please see
11 and 3 go ahead let the clouds be full
of rain they empty upon the Earth that's
where we getting our water from when you
ask about the plows go ahead and if the
trees fall towards the South or towards
the North in the place where the tree
falleth there it shall be all right so
that's all I got on that because when
you was asking about the firmament you
know it depends on what context but when
you talk about the clouds that's where
the Lord was using the water to rain
down and that's all I got on that hey
Corel yes they could write down Job 38
and 37 it'll tell you that the clouds is
also called the bottles of
Heaven oh okay yes all right thank you
for that back up there brother hope that
answered your question as we keep on
moving sister yes moving on Renee Israel
says Adam and Eve could see in the
spiritual world the tree of life and the
tree of knowledge of Good and Evil why
did she describe Satan as a serpent even
though we know Satan was not a literal
snake yes carer can you share some
light yes I can the first thing is I
don't know what you mean by sin into the
spiritual world
let me show you what I'm talking about
I'm going show you what they
saw let's let let you know because you
know spiritual world let's go to Genesis
the second chapter because they said
because she said can see in the
spiritual world I guess that's what the
tree of life and the tree of the
knowledge of Good and Evil were supposed
to be right let's show you what the
Bible said they supposed to be Genesis 2
and9 and out of the ground made the Lord
God to grow every tree that is Pleasant
to the sight and good for food the tree
of life also in the midst of the garden
and the tree of knowledge of Good and
Evil now this now where was the tree of
of Life the tree of the good and even
the tree of life was according to the
scripture here there was in the Garden
of Eden it was on this Earth had nothing
to do with spiritual World whatever the
spiritual world might
be okay right so now what was the rest
of the
question the question
was uh since they were in the spiritual
world uh why did she describe Satan as a
serpent even though we know Satan was
not a literal
snake Okay first thing is they was in
the Garden of Eden they weren in the
spiritual world it was only god of eeden
on his Earth and the other thing is she
described Satan as a serpent because she
was told that I'm going tell you why I
said she was told that because when she
was uh uh when the God gave uh uh
uh Adam the Commandment not to eat of
this tree or stay away from it she will
still the real let's go into Genesis the
chapter and we going to start reading
now before we go to this is the third
chapter let's go into uh uh uh the
second chapter read verse 16 and
18 and the Lord God commanded the man
saying of every tree of the garden thou
mayest freely
eat but of the tree of the knowledge of
Good and Evil thou shall not eat of it
for in the day that thou eatest
therefore thou shall surely die and the
Lord God said now
now Adam was the only one that he pay
attention to this next verse here
reading and the Lord God said is that
good that the man should be alone and I
will make him and help me for
him now he was alone it's not good for
man to be alone so I'm going make him a
help meet for him so how did who did he
what did he do skip down to uh verse
21 and read 21
and the Lord God caused a deep sleep to
fall upon Adam and he slept and he took
one of his ribs and closed up the Flesh
and stad thereof and the rib which the
Lord God had taken for man made he a
woman and brought her unto the
man now do now she was
told uh because she was a real so she
couldn't possibly uh uh have
heard God uh uh gave uh Adam this
commandment now let's go in the third
chapter and read verses 2 and
3 Genesis 3 2 and
3 and the woman said unto the serpent we
may eat of the fruit of the Trees of the
garden but of the tree but of the fruit
of the tree which is in the midst of the
God and God have said ye shall not eat
of it neither shall you touch it lest
you die
now how is it that she would know that
being that she was a real when when God
gave that commandment she was told right
the same thing calling serpent Satan the
serpent she was told because there's one
of his titles let's go into Revelation
the 12th chapter and read verses
7-9 and there was a war in heaven
Michael and his angels fought against
the Dragon and the dragon fought in his
angels and prevailed it not neither was
there Place found anymore in heaven and
the Great Dragon was cast out that old
serpent called the devil and Satan which
deceiveth the whole world he was cast
out into the Earth and his angels were
cast out with him so the Lord call him a
serpent just like the Lord told Adam to
stay away from him right so Eve called
him a
serpent because she quoted
him just like on not talking to him so
he was told simple as that and all the
Commandments was given she was still a
real that's all I have to say all right
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one yes uh micia K
ask do we supposed to help people that
say they are hungry like some people
that stand on their Corner
begging all right Dre what you say that
would be a nice act go ahead absolutely
let's go to Deuteronomy 15 Deuteronomy
15 and pick it up at verse
7 Deuteronomy 15 and
7 read seven and eight we gonna skip go
ahead
brother if there be among you a poor man
of one of thy brethen within any of thy
Gates of the land which the Lord thy God
giveth thee thou shall not Harden thy
heart nor shut thy hand from thy poor
brother thou shall open thy hand wide
unto him and shall surely lend him
sufficient for his need and that which
he
wanted skip down to verse
10 for thou shall surely give him and
thy heart shall not be grieved when thou
giveth unto him because thou for this
thing the Lord thy God shall bless thee
in all thy works and in all that thou
put us thy hand
unto goad for the poor shall never cease
out of the land therefore I command thee
saying Thou shalt open thy hand wide
unto thy brother to thy poor and to thy
needy in thy land now let's go over to
Proverbs
21 Proverbs 21 and we just going to read
verse 13 there Proverbs 21 and
13 when you get it go ahead
bro whoo stoppeth his ears at the Cry of
the poor he also shall cry himself but
shall not be heard I got one more place
let's go to Luke the 6th chapter Luke
6 and I want you to read verses 30 and
Luke 630 and
31 go ahead brother give to every man
the acts of thee and of him that taketh
away thy Goods ask them not
again and as ye would that men should do
to you do ye also to them likewise so
now I'm might ask a question if you was
hungry would you want somebody to give
to you right absolutely you will so you
see somebody asking you for something
and you in the position to give do it
and Jesus said this hey when I was
hungry you gave me meat I was thirsty
you gave me drink when did we do that J
when you did it to the least of these my
brother that's right you did to me
that's all I got on yes sir brother
dreed it is better to give than to
receive it mhm yeah like a wise man once
said if you in the position of
giv you in the better position of them
that have to receive so yes sir indeed
yeah thank you for that brother I hope
that answers that question sister
Deborah time check next question yes the
time is
8:25 perol filer hard ask the Holy Ghost
spirit or comforter does this sent
Spirit have authority over all other
Holy Angels in Hebrews 1
verse4 and have them and have them to
interact with those of us seeking
salvation all right looks like you want
to start off in Hebrews 1 and14 let's go
to tanzel and then the guest caller will
share some light from there
not all ministering spirits send forth
to minister for them who shall be HS of
Salvation well the first thing is that
this this one that he talking about the
Holy
Ghost the uh spirit of the confident we
talking Gabriel here no he don't have no
authority over No Angel only God have
authority over the angel Gabriel himself
is a ministering Spirit he's a
servant and and they ser and they sent
for for to serve who to serve those of
Salvation which of us but they don't
have no in reaction with
us not the only thing they do some if if
you are a servant they'll protect you
let's go into Psalm 46 and read verse 6
and
7 46 6 I'm sorry I'm sorry Psalms 346
and 7 I'm having a hard time with
scripture tonight 346 and 7 Psalms 346
and7 the poor man cth and the Lord heard
him and save him out of all his troubles
and the angel of the Lord encampeth
round about them that fear Him and
delivered
them now that's about the only time you
get some individual uh attention because
if you're Ser of God he have his angels
protected you that's
right for interacting with him you don't
even know he's
there okay and no angel and and and
Gabel don't have no Authority he is a
serving Spirit God tell him to go he go
and he tell him to come he come like all
the rest of the Angels Satan included
that's all I have to say all right hope
that answers your question as we move
on yes we can talk right here says the
the Commandments say make no image of
things in heaven or under the sea so is
it okay to draw angels as long as you
don't worship
them so Jerome share some
light no it's it's no script against
drawing Angels but you know that it is
script against worshiping Angels so
let's just go to Exodus 20 read verse 4
and
5 when you get it go ahead and
read thou shall not make unto thee any
Graven image or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above or that is in
the earth beneath or that is in the
water under the Earth thou sh Not Bow
Down thyself to them nor serve them why
the Lord thy God L jealous God visiting
the iniquities of the fathers upon the
children unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate
me that's all I got on
it all right thank you for that brother
sister Deborah let's go into a new
territory yes let's go we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday October the
2nd 20 October the
2024 I Chuck wuo Alan says during one of
our case study in school about a client
who is a rapist one of the
treatment plans my professor came up
with was teaching our client how to
masturbate is masturbation a sin is it
okay
okay guess
call let's go to First
John thir chapter and read verse
4 First John 3 and
four who so commit sins transgresseth
also the law for sin is the
transgression of the
law now when I go and I lead read the
Commandments I don't see masturbation in
there Pro or
con so you don't have no Bible that can
tell you not to or tell you that you can
but I say one thing when the Lord
created
man male and created Adam and Eve he
said be fruitful and multiply and
replenish the earth now if you can can
you I ask you a question can you make a
baby by
masturba that's all I have to
say all right we're going to move on to
our next question
s yes I Chuck wama also says can you
please explain Genesis 38 vers
8-10 Genesis 38 8-10 10 genis 388
through1 and the guest caller would take
it from
there and Judas said unto on go unto
that 's wife and married her and raise
up seed to that brother and on that knew
that the seed should not be his and it
came to pass when he went in in in in
into his brother's wife that he spilled
It On The Ground lest that he should
give seed to his brother and the thing
which he did displeased the Lord so
wherefore he slew him
also now let let's let's let's show you
what happened it was the Lord Israel
let's go read it let's go into
Deuteronomy the 25th chapter and we're
going to read verses
5-10 Deuteronomy 25 verse
5-10 if brethen dwell if Brethren dwell
together and one of them die and have no
child the wife of the Dead shall not
marry without unto a stranger her
husband brother shall go in unto her and
take her to him to wife and perform the
duty of a husband brother unto her and
it shall was that was a custom of Israel
if you had a brother he he was married
and and you w married of course and uh
uh he died didn't have no children then
you was then you were supposed to marry
his wife and have a child by her and the
child was going to be dedicated to your
brother which was passed on that is
but keep
read and it shall be that the firstborn
which she Bears shall succeed in the
name of his brother which is dead that
his name be not put out of
Israel and if the man like not to take
his brother's wife then let his brother
wife go up to the gate unto the elders
and say my husband brother refuses to
raise up unto his brother a name in
Israel when I perform the duty of my
husband's brother
then the Elders of the city shall call
him and speak unto him if he stand to it
and say I like not to take her then
shall his brother's wife come unto him
in the presence of the elders and loose
him loose his shoes from off his foot
and spit in his face and shall answer
and say so shall it be done unto that
man that would not build up his
brother's house and his name shall be
called in Israel the house of him that
have his SHO
Lo now see and that's what judah's son
should have did he didn't want the woman
he should have went through and and say
I don't want to marry this woman then
they would have brought the woman
calling she to come in she Lo his shoe
and spit in his face and he'd have been
called one with the loose shoe but no he
didn't want to do that he wanted to get
in the flesh he want to lay with the
woman and don't do the rest of it that's
why the Lord killed him because that's
evil
you know what the law
is it's all I have to say all right hope
that answered your question as we move
on to the next one yes
Lander um says in 2 Kings 3 verse 26 and
27 the king of Moab sacrific his son and
great indignation falls on Israel
why did they withdraw if God promised
Victory and did God react to the
sacrifice brother Jerome what you
got let's go read it brother
tzel second
Kings chapter 2 verse 26 and
27 I'm sorry chapter 3 verse 26 and
27 you get it go ahead and read
and with the king of Moab saw that the
battle was too sore for him he took with
him 700 men and Drew swords to break
through even unto the king of Edom but
they could not and he took his eldest
son that should have reigned in this
dead and offered him for a burnt
offering upon the wall there was a great
indignation against Israel and they
departed from him and returned to their
own
land okay so um it it wasn't
uh the the Israelites that withdrew in
this verse it was actually uh the king
of
Moab and 700 men that was with
him and they
withdrew and they went from this place
where the king of Mo
Moab sacrificed his Elder
son okay and it was the uh moabites that
had indignation against the
children of Israel because they was def
the children of Israel was defe
defeating them you know and so that was
one of the reasons why he chose the king
of Moab to sacrifice his son and the
place where they was sa went to
sacrificed his son him and 700 his men
they the ones that returned to their own
land and and as far as the uh the second
question did the Lord react to the uh
sacrifice it don't say um what God's
reaction was to the king of Moab
sacrificing his son for a burnt offering
but we know according to the word of God
it's evil in the sight of God all right
so let's go to Second Kings chapter 17
and read verse 16 and
17 17 chapter uh 2 King verse 16 and 17
when you get it go ahead and they left
all and they and they left all the
Commandments of the Lord their God and
made them molden images even two calves
and made a grovee and worship all the
hosts of heaven and serve bael and they
caused their sons and their daughters to
pass through the fire and use Devon
naations and enchantments and sold
themselves to do evil in the sight of
the Lord to provoke him to anger yeah
that's all I got
on all right thank you for that brother
hope that answered that question next
question yes next question the K family
asks if we never ask to give us a king
in flesh and continue to let God be our
King do you think the world will be as
wicked as it is
today brother Dre what you
got yeah well you know the thing is if
if that big word if so what what
happened was Israel asked for a king
because Samuel got old and his sons
started taking bribe money and you know
perverting the Judgment of the Lord and
they did wrong God was their King and is
the thing displeased Samuel Samuel told
them what would happen and they they
went anyway and said after Samuel told
them what happened they say give us a
king like the rest of the Nations right
and so the Lord is gon to rule Israel at
the end of the day so what we talking
about here is in 1 Samuel the 8th
chapter let's just go read a little bit
of
that 1 Samuel 8 pick it up at verse one
and it came to pass when Samuel was old
that he made his sons judge over
Israel now the name of the firstborn was
Joel and the name of the second zayah
and they were judge in be Sheba judges
and his sons walked not in his ways but
turned aside after Luca and took bribes
and perverted
judgment and all the Elders of Israel
gathered themselves together and came to
Samuel to Rama and said unto him behold
Thou Art old and thy Sons walk not in
thy ways now make unto us a king to
judge us like all the nations but this
things go ahead go
ahead but the thing displeased Samuel
when they said give us a king to judge
us and Samuel prayed unto the
Lord go ahead and the Lord said un
Samuel hearken unto the voice of the
people and all that they say unto thee
for they have not rejected thee but they
have rejected me that I should not Reign
Over them so there's a lot that went on
but the elders came afterwards and they
said we want a king like the Nations and
and the thing displeased Samuel because
this was an
excuse right you know but at the end end
of the day the Lord is going to rule
over Israel so that if part we ain't G
to deal with that as much let's go to
Ezekiel the 20th
chapter Ezekiel the 20th
chapter and you can read the rest of
that that 1 Samuel 8 on your own is it's
got some stuff in me first Sam uh
Ezekiel 20 20th chapter and pick it up
at verse 3
pick it up in verse uh 32 go ahead and
that which cometh unto your mind shall
not be at all that ye say we will be as
the Heathen as a families of the country
to serve wood and
stone as I live sayth the Lord God
surely with a mighty hand and with the
stressed out on and with Fury poured out
will I rule over you so the Lord is
going to come and heal is going to rule
Israel with an iron hand and he is going
to purge out the rebels in the
wilderness right and those that want to
transgress his word and they will not
enter
in so this is what's going to happen now
what has happened is Israel has rejected
the word but the Lord is gonna have a
Remnant so I I hope that that helps
because we we don't deal with the If
part as much okay
all right that's it my brother yes sir
we don't deal with the if and boy that
was a foolish request wasn't
it yes sir all right thank you for that
brother hope that answered that question
next question sister yes next question L
om Moore asks do God know your
thoughts yes um the one that created the
brain yeah let's go and read read a few
places uh tanzel therefore we go go in
at Job 42
first job
42 and you gonna read that verse uh one
and two and then we'll go go the Psalms
139 but job 42 read that one and two for
me when you get there
brother then job answered the Lord and
said I know that thou canest do
everything and that no thought can be
withholden from thee oh so if you can't
hold no thoughts look like it's some
reading on the mind going on there
Psalms 139 brother Psalms
139 let me get Psalms 139 let's read uh
one and two and then we gonna skip down
Psalm 139 1 and two go ahead oh Lord
thou H has searched me and known me thou
knowest my downsitting and my
Uprising thou understandest my thoughts
a far
off so sometime look like Lord know what
you thinking for you
thinking all right Brothers down to 23
and
24 search me oh God and know my heart
try me and know my thoughts yes and see
if there be any wicked way in me and
Lead Me in the way of
everlasting yep some sometime you can be
thinking evil God know it and hey
sometime we need help to get that up out
of there Psalms uh 94 and 11 and we got
one more Psalms 94
And1 one verse and that's Psalms 94 and
11 the Lord knoweth the thoughts of man
that they are vanity
guilty Matthews let's over there
Matthews 9 brother and read 1-4 and
let's see what Jesus said right
here sometime we get that foolishness in
our mind and we need God to help us
right Matthew 9 read 1-4 for me brother
go ahead and he entered into a ship and
passed over and came into his own City
it's Jesus here go ahead and behold they
brought to him a man sick of the py
lying on the bed and Jesus seeing their
faith said unto the sick of pausy son be
of good cheer thy sins be forgiven thee
uhhuh and behold certain of the scribes
said within them themselves this man
blasphemy now they said within
theirselves you know sometimes you can
be thinking something that ain't right
and what did Jesus saying verse four and
Jesus knowing their thoughts said
wherefore think ye evil in your hearts
yes sir so yeah do God know your
thoughts he most certainly do and that's
all all I got on
that and we hope that answered your
question we going to keep it moving to
the next one sister time is a ticket yes
let's move on brother Israel says help
me to understand Micah 4
verse5 is the Lord okay with others
having Gods help them to understand that
Micah 4 and5 brother Julius let's go to
micel four and five brother tzel
and let's let's let's understand what
this is really talking
about Isaiah
Micah 4 and read verse five and then
we're gonna show you that this is really
talking about uh when the Lord return to
this Earth this prophecy go ahead and
read all people will walk everyone in
the name of his God and we will walk in
the name of the Lord Our God forever and
now now that sounds like people going to
be going after other gods no absolutely
not back all the way up and start at
verse
one but in the last day it shall come to
pass that the mountain of the house of
the Lord shall be established in the top
of the mountains it shall be exalted
above the hills and people shall flow
unto it and people shall flow unto it
this is when the Lord come back and set
his kingdom up in Jerusalem go ahead and
many nations shall come and say come and
let us go up to the mountain of the Lord
and to the house of the god of Jacob and
he would teach us of his ways and we
will walk in his path for the law shall
go forth from Zion and the word of the
Lord from Jerusalem so now all n Israel
is just one nation but the Nations that
are still here when the Lord come they
going to come up to Jerusalem and
worship
and uh and the god
that they will serve will be the only
true and living God the god of Israel
let me show you what I'm talking about
Isaiah 45 quickly Isaiah 45 and I got
one spot after that uh brother Cornel
Isaiah 40 Isaiah 45 Isaiah 45 yes sir
Isaiah 45 at verse 19 the end of 19 says
I I the Lord speak righteousness I
declare things that are right verse 20
what do verse 20 say assemble yourselves
and come near together ye that are
Escape of the Nations they have no
knowledge that set up the wood of their
Graven image and pray unto gods that
cannot save and pray unto a God that
cannot save why can he save back up and
read verse
five I am the lord and there was none
else there is no God besides me I G thee
though that thou that known me he said
ain't no other God so these people that
got all these pagan gods they're pagan
they're not Gods but all these nations
that's going to come up is going to come
and worship the god of Israel how do I
know last place the 56th chapter of
Isaiah verses 6 and
7 Micah told you all the nations gonna
come and worship him go ahead at verse
six and seven go
ahead Isaiah 566 and 7
go
ahead are you muted I think he's having
some uh technical difficulties so I'll
read it Julius go ahead also the sons of
the stranger that join themselves to the
Lord to serve him and to love the name
of the Lord to be his servants everyone
that keepeth the Sabbath from polluting
and taketh hold of my Covenant even them
will I bring to my holy Mount and make
them joyful In My House of Prayer their
burnt offerings and their sacrifices
shall be accepted upon mine Altar for
mine house shall be called an House of
Prayer for all people so in Micah the
5th chapter fourth chapter verse 5 those
people's God will be the god of Israel I
hope that
help yes sir can you guys hear
me back
all right thank you for that brother
let's go to our next
question yes Israel longar says in
Jeremiah
35: 6 7 18 and 19 if they sow no seed
plant no
Vineyard how will they survive and
verses 18 and 19 please
explain all right next J 35 first
starting off at 6 and S tanzel and the
guest caller take it from
there Jeremiah 356 and
yep but they said we will drink no wine
for for jonadab the son of re rehab Our
Father commanded us saying you shall
drink no wine neither ye nor your sons
forever neither shall ye build house nor
sow seed nor plant Vineyards nor have
any but all your days ye shall dwell in
tents that ye may live many days in the
land where ye be
strangers okay and then
verse I'll get down to that but the
first thing is uh uh this uh uh this guy
God paid attention to how these guys
kept the father's
Commandments and how did they make they
m in try to make a way to being a farmer
to make a
living they was new mans so they had
there are other ways of of making a
living it's just like I can't grow a uh
uh I can't grow a a
weed but I can still make a
okay I read so they was no man they
didn't build no houses they didn't they
they just went from tent to tent you
know just like they said in was the old
days where egyp used to steal used to
deal with but they made a living and
they didn't steal Now read Verse
18 and jeriah said unto the house of the
rich the re
rechabites thus say the Lord of hosts
the god of Israel because he have obeyed
the Commandment of jonadab your father
and kept all his precepts and done
according to all that he hath commanded
you now
you
know because you've done this keep
reading therefore thus say the Lord of
host the god of Israel jehonadab the son
of rad shall not want a man to stand
before me
forever and why is because the Lord knew
that they if they they were how faithful
they were these guys listen to the Lord
where Israel as a whole didn't back up
to verse 13 and read to verse
16 13 and 16 go ahead thus say the Lord
of host the god of Israel go and tell
the men of Judah and the inhabitants of
Jerusalem we will not receive
instructions to Haren hearken to my
words sayeth the Lord for the words of
jeon jonadab the son of reab that he
commanded his sons not to drink wine are
performed for unto this day they drink
none but obey their father's
Commandments notwithstanding I have
spoken unto you Rising early and
speaking but ye hearken not unto me but
I have sent also unto you all my
servants the prophets rising up early
and sending them saying return ye now
every man from his evil way and the men
your doing and go not after other gods
to serve them and you shall dwell in the
land which I have given you given to you
and your fathers but ye have not
inclined your is no hearken unto
me read the next verse because the son
of Jonah D the son of reab have
performed the Commandments of their
father which he commanded them but this
people have not hearkened unto
me now he used them he he he said these
guys here and God took care of them too
because he admired the faithfulness of
obeying the Commandment of their God of
their father so he say if Israel would
obey me like uh uh jonadab old children
obey them then
hey I save them all cuz they would keep
my Commandments Faithfully just like
they kept their dad's Commandments
that's why the Lord used them as an
example be like these guys the way they
obeyed their father and kep his
Commandments you do the same with me
because they obeyed their father and
kept his commandment they are all did
well yes they were no but they still
made a
limit and so now if you obey my
commandment like they did then you will
do well that's all I have to say all
right thank you for that hope that
answered their question sister Deborah
time surely flies when you're having
fun yes so solivan TV
say can you go to where the Bible says
this happened in Acts 7 vers 44 and
45 Julius can you take it from there
yeah Stephan is running down Israel's
history to Israel and they don't like
what he's saying so he's running our
whole history down uh he's giving us a
timeline read 44 uh acts 7
and44 we gonna take that verse first go
ahead our fathers have the Tabernacles
of witness in the wilderness as he had
appointed speaking unto Moses that he
should make it according to the fashion
that he had seen now hold this right
here let's go to Exodus the 25th chapter
and let's look at what this Tabernacle
in the wilderness was and when it was
established Exodus 25 1 and2 10 this is
the tent or the Tabernacle was a
portable tent go ahead and read and the
Lord spake unto Moses saying Speak unto
the children of Israel that they bring
men offering of every man that giveth
willingly with his heart and ye shall
take my offering and so he told him all
the material to bring to make the
Tabernacle and to furnish it skip down
to verse
eight and let them make me a sanctuary
that I may dwell among them so that
fulfill that acts 7 and44
let's go back there and read
45 and that what they had in there they
had the Ark of the Covenant okay which
meant which meant God was among Israel
and now verse
45 which also our fathers that came
after brought in with Jesus unto the
possession of the Gentiles whom God
drave out before the face of our fathers
unto the days of David now when Jesus
came on the scene they were no longer in
a pit they was in a
temple but there was the second temple
which was the temple that Herod had
built you know so uh that's the best I
can do with that uh guest caller you
have any any uh issues on that because
when Jesus came on the scene the temple
was built Herod Temple was built but the
Gentile was running the
world that was the second temple and the
Ark wasn't there at that time
best I can do with
45 right we go leave it right there look
like sister Deborah we're coming down to
our last question what is it yes uh
being elf as Hosea 12: 3 and 4 is there
other reference to Jacob's power in the
womb and he found him in bethl and he
spake with us who is he in him as being
referenced in bethl here as speaking
with God Jesus is that correct in
reference to
us all right Hosea 123 and4 10 guess
caller take it from
there he took his brother by the heel in
the womb and by his strength he had
power with God yet he had power over the
angels and prevailed and he wept and
made supplications unto him he found him
in Bethel and there he spake with
us even the Lord God of hosts the Lord
is his
memorial okay the first thing is that uh
uh let's deal with the wound part first
let's go to Genesis the 25th
chapter read verses 21 to
26 for this is the birth of Esau and
Jacob Genesis
25 uh Genesis
25 and 21 and
26 and Isaac entreated the Lord for his
wife because she was Barren and the Lord
was entreated of him and Rebecca his
wife conceived
skip down to verse
26 keep read and the children struggled
together within her and she said if it
be so why am I thus and she went to
inquire of the Lord and the Lord said
unto her two nations are in thy womb and
two manner of peoples shall be separated
from thy vows and the one people shall
be stronger than the other people and
the Elder Shall Serve the younger and
when their days was to be delivered were
fulfilled behold there were twins in her
womb and the first came out red all over
and hairy G like an hairy garden and
they called this name Esau and after
that came his brother out and his hand
took hold on Esau's Hill Esau's Hills
and his name was called Jacob and Isaac
was three score years old when she Beed
there now during that time when they
were when Jacob and Esau were strug in
the womb Esau was the oldest son but
Jacob had him by the heel that's what it
that's what this is referring to for one
thing but then let's go into Genesis as
as uh uh uh because uh uh that was the
wound struggle now let's go to Genesis
the 32nd chapter and read verses
24-
28 this is when Jacob was coming back uh
on his way back to back to the land of
Canaan after he had been gone for 20
years and uh his brother Esau was
meeting him and and and Jacob thought
that maybe Esau was going to try and
kill him so he sent everybody away from
him and he was left alone let's see what
happened Genesis 32 and verse 24-
28 and Jacob was left alone and and
there Wrestled a man with him until the
breaking of the day and when he saw saw
that he prevailed not against him he
touched the hollow of his thigh and the
hollow of Jacob's thigh was out of joint
as he wrestled with him and he said let
me go for the day break and he said I
would not let thee go except thou bless
me and he said unto him but what is thy
name and he said Jacob and he said thy
name should be called No More Jacob but
Israel for as a prince hast thou power
with God and with men and H has
prevailed
okay so that's when he changed his name
God adopted Jacob because of the prince
you have power with God and with man so
that is the that's the power he had with
God and man but then when you say in
bethl that he spoke with us let me show
you what this US mean let's go first
let's go into Genesis 1 and read verse
26 and 27
and God said let us make man in our own
image after our likeness and let them
have dominion over the fish of the sea
and over the fowls of the air and over
the cattle and over all the Earth and
over every creeping thing that creepeth
upon the
earth now we said let us make man in our
own image who who are us that Father and
Jesus because Jesus and the father are
together now let's go in Isaiah 57 read
verse
15 for thus say the high and lofty one
that inhabit eternity who name is Holy I
dwell in the high and holy place with
him also that is of a contrite and
humble Spirit to revive the spirit of
the humble and to revive the heart of
the contrite
ones so these are both gods that
inhabits eternity that's the father and
the son and so it's in Beth that he
spoke with us so when they when when
when uh uh uh Jacob spoke to the Lord he
was speaking to Jesus and the
father that's all I have to
say all
right sister Deborah uh time
check the time is
9:04 all right look it's like um we have
ran out of time and we want to thank
everybody for tuning in and if you
submitted a question and we didn't get
to it please don't resubmit it sister
Deborah take you put it in rotation and
we will deal with that question next
week so until we all come together again
we asking you all out there to be safe
be blessed and the Lord have mercy on us
all brother tanzel close us out I Our
Father which are in heaven Hallowed be
thy name thy kingdom come thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven give us
this day our daily bread and forgive us
of our debts as we forgive our Deb to
and lead us not into temptation but
Deliver Us from Evil for thine is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever in Jesus name we pray amen amen